Guide to the Moses Schallenberger Papers, 1847-1898
Department of Special Collections
Moses Schallenberger Papers,
1848-1898
Special Collections M0064
Schallenberger, Moses
13 items
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions:
None.
Provenance:
Gift of Mary Sheldon Barnes, who received them from Moses Schallenberger in 1895.
Biographical Note:
Moses Schallenberger was an early California pioneer.
Scope and Contents Note:
This collection includes correspondence and photographs covering the period after the arrival of Schallenberger in California, with an account, recorded by Mary Sheldon Barnes, of Schallenberger's overland journey to California from Missouri in 1844. Correspondents include John Townsend, Elizabeth Schallenberger Townsend, and Mary Sheldon Barnes.
Although received with the collection, items 2, 5 and 13 appear to be unrelated.
CONTAINER LIST
- Barnes, Mary S., "Schallenberger Narrative," information from a personal interview, n.d., 1; 9 pp typed
- [Morant], Emma to Lady [L]ushington, n.d., 2; 3 pp with cover
- Schallenberger, Moses, portrait photograph, 1865 Dec. 25, 3
- Schallenberger, Moses, portrait photograph, n.d., 4
- Pencil note by unknown author, apparently unrelated, n.d., 5
- Townsend [John] to Moses Schallenberger, 1847 Jan. 25, 6; 3 pp
- [Townsend, Mrs. E. L.] to Moses Schallenberger, 1848 Feb. 3, 7; 2 pp
- Schallenberger, Moses to Mrs. E. L. Townsend, 1848 Feb. 14, 8; 3 pp
- Townsend, [John] to Moses Schallenberger, with penciled Spanish phrases or poem on verso, 1849 May 31, 9; 2 pp
- Schallenberger, Moses to John Townsend, 1850 Oct. 12, 10; 3 pp
- Boggs, W. M. to Mrs. "Earl" Barnes (of Palo Alto), 1893 Jan. 18, 11; 4 pp
- Schallenberger, Moses to [Mary Sheldon] Barnes, 1895 March 26, 12; 2 pp
- [Kuftner, Anton] to [__ Tarrost], in German, 1898 [Jan.] 12, 13; 3 pp